export const quizQuestions_1 = {
  questions: [
  {
    question: 'What is the primary purpose of functional components in React?',
    choices: [
      'To manage state',
      'To handle user events',
      'To define UI elements',
      'To perform asynchronous operations',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'To define UI elements',
  },
  {
    question: 'In React, how are props passed to functional components?',
    choices: ['Via props attribute', 'As function parameters', 'Using state', 'Through refs'],
    correctAnswer: 'As function parameters',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which lifecycle method is not available in functional components?',
    choices: ['componentDidMount', 'componentWillUnmount', 'render', 'componentDidUpdate'],
    correctAnswer: 'componentDidMount',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the alternative to the "this" keyword in functional components?',
    choices: ['self', 'props', 'state', 'No alternative needed'],
    correctAnswer: 'No alternative needed',
  },
  {
    question: 'In React, what is the purpose of the useState hook?',
    choices: [
      'To create class components',
      'To manage and update state in functional components',
      'To define event handlers',
      'To import external libraries',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'To manage and update state in functional components',
  },
  {
    question: 'How do you pass data from a parent component to a child component in React?',
    choices: [
      'Using the parent component state',
      'Via props',
      'Through the context API',
      'Using refs',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Via props',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the significance of the key prop in React lists?',
    choices: [
      'It determines the order of elements in the list',
      'It uniquely identifies each element in the list',
      'It is required for conditional rendering',
      'It is used for styling purposes',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'It uniquely identifies each element in the list',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which of the following is a valid way to conditionally render content in React?',
    choices: [
      'Using if-else statements in the render method',
      'Using the && operator',
      'Using the ternary operator',
      'All of the above',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the purpose of the useEffect hook in React?',
    choices: [
      'To handle user input',
      'To manage state changes',
      'To perform side effects in functional components',
      'To define component lifecycle methods',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'To perform side effects in functional components',
  },
  {
    question: 'How can you prevent the default behavior of an event in React?',
    choices: [
      'By using event.preventDefault()',
      'By returning false from the event handler',
      'By setting the event\'s default property to false',
      'React does not allow preventing default behavior',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'By using event.preventDefault()',
  },
],
}

export default quizQuestions_1;